Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/linustorvalds (LinkedIn) kernel.org (Other) git.or.cz/ (Other)

Top Skills

Linux

qit

Scuba Diving

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Finnish (Native or Bilingual)
Swedish (Native or Bilingual)

Linus Torvalds

Fellow at Linux Foundation

Portland, Oregon, United States

Summary

Main Linux kernel developer since 1991, still active maintainer.

Original architect and author of the 'Git' source control management system, still active in development but no longer the primary maintainer.

Specialties: System programming - Linux and git

Experience

Linux Foundation

Fellow

July 2003 - Present (21 years 11 months)

Open Source Development Labs (OSDL)

Fellow

July 2003 - December 2006 (3 years 6 months)

Previous name for the Linux Foundation, before the merger with LSB

Transmeta Corp

Fellow

March 1997 - June 2003 (6 years 4 months)

Education

University of Helsinki

MSc, Computer Science · (1989 - 1996)

Helsingin yliopisto

Honorary Doctorate, Computer Science · (1988 - 1996)

Stockholm University

Honorary Doctorate, Mathematics and Science · (1999)